A Guide to the Libraries and Educational Technologies Records, 1939-2016, bulk 1988-2009: UA 0008
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Subject Files, 1973-2013
  - Gov Docs – Political Science, 2001-2012 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Gov Docs – Serial Set Survey, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Gov Docs – US Periodical Index, 1991-1996 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Gov Docs – Virginia Materials, 1988-1995 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - History Department, 2002 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - IT/ILS/ILR Directors Group 1998 (Folder 1 of 2), 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - IT/ILS/ILR Directors Group 1998 (Folder 2 of 2), 1998-1999 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - JMU Library Journal Review, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Journals-Madison College Profile 1975, 1975-1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Journal Review Project 2000, 2000 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Library and Educational Technologies Goals FY 2005-2006, 2005-2006 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Library Organization Charts, 2012-2013 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - LibQUAL+, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Library Self Study Report, 2006, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Library Self Study Report (Copy 2), 2006, 2007 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Library Self-Study Final Report, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Library Self-Study Report Drafts, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Library Self-Study Report Volume 1: Report and Appendices 1-8, 1998 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Library Self-Study Report Volume 2: Appendices 9-14, 1998 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - MARCIVE, 2007-2008 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Media Relations, 1991-1999 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Memos, 1996-2002, 2004 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Memos, emails, 1975-2002 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Memorandums (Folder 1 of 3), 1990-1995 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Misc. Memorandums (Folder 2 of 3), 1990-1995 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Misc. Memorandums (Folder 3 of 3), 1990-1995 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Mission Statement JMU, 1991-1995 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Periodical Use Study, 1984-1991, 1993, 1998 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Publications, 1996, 2007, circa 2008, undated (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Self-Study Manual 1980-1981, circa 1989 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Shenandoah Valley Business Information & Instruction Gateway, 2002-2005 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Small Business, 2001 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Special Collections (Folder 1 of 3), 1981-2009 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Special Collections (Folder 2 of 3), 1981-2009 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Special Collections (Folder 3 of 3), 1981-2009 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Special Collections Annual Reports (Folder 1 of 2), 1982-1995 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Special Collections Annual Reports (Folder 2 of 2), 1982-1995 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Special Collections Barbour Collection, 1999-2000 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Special Collections Brochures, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Special Collections ETD Files (Folder 1 of 2), 2008-2009 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Special Collections ETD Files (Folder 2 of 2), 2008-2009 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Special Collections Manuscript Index, 2004 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Special Collections Student Internships, 1984-2005 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Student Affairs Office (Folder 1 of 2), 1989-2000 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Student Affairs Office (Folder 2 of 2), 1989-2000 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Various Library Reports, 1985-1988 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Teaching AND Learning, 1999, undated (Box 23, Folder 5)
- Library Faculty and Staff, 1986-2003
  Series 5: Library Faculty and Staff, 1986-2003 contains documents relating to the work of library faculty and staff. Included in this series are faculty responsibility self-surveys, records from faculty and staff retreats/workshops, minutes from library department head meetings and liaison/faculty meetings. Also included are records and consideration of faculty and staff salaries and leave, performance assessment, and professional development. One item of interest is the development of a Mission Statement for Carrier Library, and a resulting strategic plan for the future of the library. Other items of interest are individual Meyers-Briggs results from staff workshops and faculty activity surveys.
  Items housed within Faculty Activity Survey RESTRICTED, 1993, 1995, 1998, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 8) are accessible to researchers. Because of personal information found on the documents, researchers agree to make no notes or other recordation of privacy protected information found within this folder, and further agree not to publish or disclose such information for any purpose.
  - Catalog Dep. Retreat 9/86, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Faculty Activity Survey, (SELECTED ITEMS REMOVED TO RESTRICTED), 1993, 1995, 1998, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Activity Survey RESTRICTED, 1993, 1995, 1998, 2001 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Mission Statement Carrier Library, 1988-1991, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Library Faculty (Folder 1 of 2), 1991-1996, 2000-2003 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Library Faculty (Folder 2 of 2), 1991-1996, 2000-2003 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - L+ET Faculty Workload Forms, 2001-2002, 2001-2002 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Library Dept. Heads, 1984, 1994-2000, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Personnel, 1997-1998, 2000-2003, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Professional Development Of Library Faculty, 1987-2002 (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Technical Services Retreat '90, 1990 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Library History, 1939-2016
  Series 6: Library History, 1939-2016 contains materials documenting significant events in the history of the library. Included in this series are news articles relating to the library, plans for library expansion and development, and ephemera from key library events. Also included in this series are pamphlets and documents outlining library skills and procedures, a timeline of library construction, and photographs of library staff. The Library Scrapbook, 1939-1941 housed within Box 28 is of particular interest. The scrapbook contains newspaper clippings and some copies of photographs documenting the first two years of Madison Memorial Library. Another item of interest, is correspondence from Madison College alumni Mary Wright Thrasher ('41) found in Box 26, Folder 1. In this letter to the former Dean, Ralph Alberico, she briefly mentions her remembrances of the library as a student when the library was housed in Harrison Hall. She also mentions that Carrier Library was not built until a few years after she graduated in 1941, although it opened to students in 1939. Items in Map Case 3:1 include architectural renderings of Rose Library showing placement of furniture on each floor of the library as well as architectural renderings for a new security entrance as well as poster titled New Library for the College of Integrated Science and Technology Campus, October 2004 with images of the CISAT campus with some construction being done. Also included in the map case are old Carrier Library floor plans.
  - Bookplates and Bookmarks, undated (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Building Expansion + Renovations (Folder 1 of 3), 1988-1995, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Building Expansion + Renovations (Folder 2 of 3), 1988-1995, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Building Expansion + Renovations (Folder 3 of 3), 1988-1995, 1999-2000 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Card Catalog Sorter, undated (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Carrier Exhibits, 1989-1998 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Carrier Library Floor Plans, xxxx (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Carrier Front Reopening, 2016 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Carrier Library 75th Anniversary Ephemera, 2014 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Carrier Library Building Guide, ca. 1984 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Carrier Library Dedication Ephemera, 1984 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Carrier and Rose Library Architectural Drawings and Poster, 2004-2013, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Chris Bolgiano Retirement, 2005 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence,, 2006 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Contract Manual, Carrier Library, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Depository Stickers, undated (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Invitation for Bids, CISAT Library, Vol. 1 of 2 (Folder 1 of 2), 2006 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Invitation for Bids, CISAT Library, Vol. 1 of 2 (Folder 2 of 2), 2006 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - nvitation for Bids, CISAT Library, Vol. 2 of 2 (Folder 1 of 2), 2006 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - nvitation for Bids, CISAT Library, Vol. 2 of 2 (Folder 2 of 2), 2006 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - nvitation for Bids, CISAT Library, Vol. 1 of 2, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - nvitation for Bids, CISAT Library, Vol. 2 of 2, 2006 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - JMU News: "Madison Memorial Library: Standing Room Only,", ca. 1980 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Laird L. Conrad Memorial Law Library Ephemera, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Laird L. Conrad Memorial Law Library Founding Documents, 1963-1987 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Library Addition 1982, 1978-1984 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Library Development, 1971, 1986, 2001-2002, 2008 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Library Instruction, 1989-1990, 2003-2005 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Library Scrapbook, 1939-1941 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Library Scrapbook (copy), 1939-1941 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Library Skills Workbooks, 1983-1987 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Library Skills Workbooks, 1990, 1992 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Library Skills Workbooks, 1994, 1995 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Madison Memorial Library Archival Founding Papers (Folder 1 of 2), 1970-1979 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Madison Memorial Library Archival Founding Papers (Folder 2 of 2), 1970-1979 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Madison Memorial Library Dedication, 1939 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Madison Memorial Library Handbooks and Guides, 1968-1975, 1978 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Madison Memorial Library Quart., 1976-1978 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Madison Memorial "Moving Experience" Button, 1982 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Media Resources Carrier Library Handbook, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Media Items, 2003, 2005-2009, 2014, undated (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Music Library, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - News Articles, 1984, 2009 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Photographs-Library Staff, 1977-1982 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases – Library Addition, 1977-1981 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Ralph Alberico Retirement, 2014 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Rose Library Architectural Floor Plans and Images, ca. 2005 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Rose Library Architectural Plan, 2009 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Rose Library Bid Documents, 2004 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Rose Library Bid Documents (Folder 1 of 3), 2006 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Rose Library Bid Documents (Folder 2 of 3), 2006 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Rose Library Bid Documents (Folder 3 of 3), 2006 (Box OV 1, Folder 4)
  - Rose Library Design Documents, 2005 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Rose Library Ephemera, 2008, 2014 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Rose Library Promotional Material, 2006 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Thomas McLaughlin, 1980, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Timeline of the Construction of Madison Memorial Library, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)